BRILLIANT FIKRI

+62 813 - 3148 - 7753 | briliantfikri@gmail.com | Surabaya, Jawa Timur, Indonesia

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/brilliantfikri/ | Portfolio: https://bryaanf.github.io/MyPortfolio/

LATAR PROFESIONAL

Pengembang perangkat lunak dengan pengalaman dalam membangun aplikasi web yang andal dan efisien. Berpengalaman menggunakan teknologi seperti WAMP stack dengan Laravel dan MERN stack. Mampu menciptakan solusi perangkat lunak yang berdampak, menyederhanakan proses bisnis, dan meningkatkan efektivitas kinerja. Berorientasi pada hasil dengan fokus pada kode berkualitas dan penyelesaian proyek tepat waktu.

PENGALAMAN KERJA

Asisten Praktikum untuk Mata Kuliah Jaringan Komputer dan Pemrograman Januari 2024 - Juni 2024 Framework

- Membantu pengajaran materi Jaringan Komputer dan Pemrograman Framework.
- Mengembangkan materi pembelajaran baru untuk meningkatkan efektivitas praktikum.

Magang Pengembang Website di Kejaksaan Tinggi Jawa Timur Agustus 2023 - September 2023

- Mengembangkan aplikasi Sistem Informasi Geografis (SIG) untuk memetakan ketersediaan eselon.
- Memimpin tim untuk menyelesaikan proyek dalam waktu 3 minggu dengan hasil berkualitas tinggi.

Magang Pengembang Website di Lintasarta Surabaya

Juli 2019 - September 2019

- Membangun sistem CRM untuk data pelanggan perusahaan.
- Berkolaborasi dan memimpin tim untuk menyelesaikan proyek dalam waktu 1 bulan.

REFERENSI PROYEK

Sistem Informasi SDM PT. Indo Global Impex

- Deskripsi: Pengembangan sistem untuk manajemen sumber daya manusia.
- Teknologi: Laravel, MySQL, Bootstrap.

Aplikasi Sistem Informasi Geofrafis Kejaksaan Tinggi Jawa Timur

- Deskripsi: Aplikasi pemetaan ketersediaan eselon.
- Teknologi: JavaScript, Leaflet.js, Laravel, Bootstrap, MySql.

Sistem CRM PT. Aplikanusa Lintasarta area Surabaya

- Deskripsi: Sistem manajemen pelanggan untuk penyedia layanan internet.
- Teknologi: PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap.

PENDIDIKAN

Jurusan Sistem Informasi di Universitas Telkom Surabaya

2020 - 2024

- IPK: 3.62
- Proyek Akhir: "Pengembangan Sistem Informasi Sumber Daya Manusia dengan Metode Extreme Programming (Studi Kasus: PT. Indo Global Impex)"

Sekolah Menengah Kejuruan (SMK) dengan Jurusan Teknik Jaringan Komputer

2017 - 2020

• Fokus: Teknik Komputer dan Jaringan, Administrasi Sistem Jaringan, IoT, Teknologi Layanan Jaringan

KEMAMPUAN DAN TUJUAN

- **Kemampuan Teknis:** HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Tailwind, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, React Native, PHP, Laravel, Codelgniter, Python, Java, API Development, Database Management, GIT, SDLC Agile, Full Stack Development, Konfigurasi Jaringan Komputer, Hosting, Microsoft Office.
- Kemampuan Non-Teknis: Pemecahan Masalah, Kerja Tim, Adaptif, Kepemimpinan, Komunikasi.
- Bahasa: Bahasa Indonesia (Asli), Inggris (Conversational / Nilai EPrT : 563), Jawa (Asli).
- **Tujuan Karir**: Menciptakan solusi perangkat lunak inovatif yang mendukung efisiensi bisnis dan memberikan nilai tambah bagi organisasi. Berkomitmen untuk terus belajar dan berkembang dalam industri teknologi untuk memecahkan berbagai masalah ril yang berdampak besar.

BRILLIANT FIKRI

+62 813 - 3148 - 7753 | briliantfikri@gmail.com | Surabaya, East Java, Indonesia

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/brilliantfikri/ | Portfolio: https://bryaanf.github.io/MyPortfolio/

INTRODUCTION

I am a software developer with experience in delivering reliable web applications. Specializing in WAMP stack with laravel and MERN stack, I have successfully contributed to various projects by ensuring code quality, meeting deadlines, and aligning solutions with client needs. My goal is to create impactful software that simplifies processes and provides value to users.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lab Assistant in Computer Network and Framework Programming Subject

Jan 2024- June 2024

- Help lecturer to teach student about the subject, impacting on effective and efficiency of lecturer day to day work of lecturer working hours.
- Preparing for new material update for the class and make sure the content easily understandable by the student.
- Implemented a troubleshooting errors encountered by students in practical sessions, reducing the average resolution time for them to finish the project.

Website Developer Intern at Kejaksaan Tinggi Jawa Timur

Aug 2023 - Sep 2023

- Creating apps for mapping echelon availability inside work area of Kejaksaan Tinggi Jawa Timur on Kejaksaan Negeri branch with GIS (Geographic Information Systems).
- Lead my fellow intern team to ensure we reach the goal on time and ensure we deliver quality project in just 2 weeks and 1 weeks for finalizing the product done total in 3 weeks only.

Website Developer Intern at Lintasarta Surabaya

July 2019 - Sep 2019

- Make a customer relationship management website to store customer network data since the company work as internet service provider and ensure the website is working as company needs.
- Collaborate, communicate, and lead my fellow intern to ensure we deliver high quality project on time in just 3 weeks and 1 week for releasing the product with total 1 month work only from 3 month given.

EDUCATION

Information Systems Major at Telkom University Surabaya

Aug 2020 - Oct 2024

- Graduate with last GPA 3.62.
- Final Project on "Human Resource Information Systems Development with Extreme Programming Method (Study Case: PT. Indo Global Impex)".

Vocational High School with Computer Network Egineering major at Telkom Schools Malang

Aug 2017 - Sep 2020

Relevant coursework: Computer and Network Engineering, Network Infrastructure Administration, Telecommunication Engineering, Network Service Technology, Internet of Things (IoT), Network System Administration.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Technical Skills: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, React. Native, PHP, Laravel, Code Igniter, Python, Java, Project Management, API Development, Version Control System (GIT), SDLC Agile Methodologies, Database Management, SQL, Full Stack Development, Computer Network Configuration, Server Configuration, Hosting Configuration, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Power Point, Outlook).
- Non Technical Skills: Problem Solving, Team Work, Adaptive, Leadership, Communication.
- Languages: English (Conversational / EPrT Score: 563), Bahasa Indonesia (Native), Java (Native).
- Certifications: Full Stack Web Development at Buildwithangga, Figma UI/UX Design Essentials at Udemy.